Hello.
The next feature we're going to add to our game is going to be a slide mechanic, so our player character
will be able to slide along the walls inside of our game.
To get started, I want us to create a new folder and just call this levels.
Then we go to file.
I'm going to select new level.
Then select the basic.
Click create.
And then go save.
And then save this inside of our levels folder and just pull this prototype.
Want to level out.
I want you to go to the player character folder and just make sure that this level has the 2D game mode.
And we just want to go here and go basics and add a player start.
And then I want us to go add and go shapes and just add this cube.
And just go.
Select and scale objects.
And just make us keep quiet.
Oh.
And I'll just go play.
The idea here is, Oops.
So I'm gonna make my cube a bit thicker as well.
The idea here is I'm going to make it all my plan sliding along the wall.
They're going to play a wall, sliding animation.
And when this writing on the wall, my plane about to jump off the wall and be launched in the opposite
direction.
So to set that up, let's head over to our player, BP.
And I'm just going to come in all these notes, all the dash.
And we just want to find some free space and just right click and look for a vent.
It.
So the way this event hit will work.
It's whenever our players collision hits anything, this node will fire and of event hit.
We want to check if the other actor we've hit has a particular tag.
So for other drag has tag this one actor has tag.
And the tag we're going to be looking for is Wolf.
And we just want to drink up at four.
And Julian.
So we're going to check to see if our black actor is being an actor, which has the tag, which is warm.
And we're going to be checking to see if our player character is also falling in the air, because I
only want my character to do a wall slide if they're falling.
So we can drag in our character movement track off here and the floor is falling and then just hook
this up here.
I love this and I'm a for branch.
So if my character hit something and has the tiger and they're falling, then I'll tell the game that
we should be wall sliding.
So we create a new variable before it will start.
Question Mark And I'll just drag this in here and just check it.
So it's true.
Then we just want to try and look for retrievable.
Too late.
So the way this node will work is as long as this is constantly cooled, its node won't fire.
So as long as we're on a wall, this node will not fire.
However, if after 0.1 seconds, there's no does not fire.
That means my plan must not be on a wall.
So we're just going to copy this node and tell the game that we're not wall siding.
So I'm just going to go compile.
And just so that we can test that everything is working.
I'm just going to drive up here and look for print shrink.
And I meant to say on a roll.
And I'm just going to copy this, paste this here, and then I'll make a say, not on the wall.
And if you just go compile, save and close this.
If I just let my cube go.
Details and search for tag.
It's going to go.
Actor And I just want to click this little add element and I'll give this the war tag.
So now if I go next to this war, my play character is fallen.
It should print string on a wall.
If I go play and I jump next to this wall, it says, On a wall.
On a wall.
And as you can see, when I reached the bottom, it said, not on a wall.
So the next thing you need to do is make it so it plays an animation when our character is on a wall.
Next, if we head over to our character's animation blueprint.
We're going to use a Trump node whenever our character is sliding along a wall so that they play that
wall sliding animation.
So if we just right click for Trump, just call this on a wall.
And we're going to make it play our wars like animation.
So if you just drag up here and look for animation, see it, and just cool this sliding.
And just head inside here.
And we're just going to play our Wolf Lightning animation.
Then we're going to hook from one sighting to our run.
So once we stop all siding and we're on the ground, we want to enter our Idol run state.
So if we head inside here in order to enter that state, we want to check out the character is on the
ground.
So we'll drag in our player reference.
And we'll just up here and for is walking.
We also want to check that our character has stopped or sliding.
So in order to do that, we can drag in our player, our hunts.
And if you remember, we made this variable to tell us whether we're on a wall or whether we're off
a wall.
So if we just drag up, if we want to look for is all sliding.
So I pulled a wall slide saying, get waterlogged and we want to check that this variable is not true.
So we just drag up here and look for the not boolean.
If this Bible is not true and my character is walking, then we will enter our search one step.
So we just drag and go and boolean and hook this into here.
If both of these conditions are true, then we'll enter our idol such front state.
So one more war siding.
We could also just enter our fooling state if our character decides to jump off the wall.
So for that reason, we need to hook up from wall slide to here.
And we double click in hand side here.
We want to check to see if our character is falling.
So we'll get our player VP reference trophy.
And the fourth is falling.
And we'll also check that we're not all riding.
So I'll drag my play of reference again and look for wool slide.
And again, we want to check that this is not true.
So I'm not for not ruling.
And these conditions to be true in order to enter the state.
So I drove up here and Vivian and Jess hook us up here.
And go compile.
So that's the animation sorted for this.
Next, let's head over to our play a blueprint and we'll make it so that whenever we're on a wall it
will jump to the on a wall state inside of our animation blueprint.
So to do that, if we just drag in our animation component and to look for the anim instance.
I'm just going to delete this note and we just want to drive up here and for Trump to note Trump, we're
going to be jamming to.
I called mine on a wall.
Again, this needs to be spelt correctly, otherwise it won't work.
So actually I called it on.
I'm just going to copy it and paste it here and connect this into here.
So now when I'm on a walk, I will jump to that state.
We can compile and test this all out.
So now they're going to play.
And I jump on a wall.
I'll play my wall signing animation.
So it looks a bit off.
So my characters are bit away from the wall.
We're going to work on fixing that next.